Here the word of God.
What I have
tonight from the Lord is a word of
exhortation.
I discovered that we are living at a
time when so many people are
discouraged.
I've talked to quite a number of people.
And as you talk to them,
you discover that they are discouraged
and disappointed.
Some to an extent of going back from
this faith
because of the issues we have in the
world today.
Because every message of the world today
is bad.
All news
which we hear in the world today are bad
news.
And so many people are discouraged. Some
from their places of work, some from
their homes, some because of their
businesses, others because of their
studies, others because of the state and
the nature of the work they are in and
what they are doing. And so many other
things. Some parents are disappointed
because of their children. Some children
are also disappointed because of their
parents. And you'll discover that so
many people are there but walking in
disappointments.
Some go to pray and they find that they
can't pray through because they are
praying from a bitter heart because of
the things that are
weighing them down. But this evening, I
want us to trust the Lord that whatever
kind of a situation you're going
through, the Lord is going to come
through for us. Probably you've waited
upon the Lord for some time and he seems
to have tarried to an extent that you
ask yourself, is really the Lord hearing
me? Is he really the Lord there? Where
is this God whom I trust in? Let me tell
you he's there.
And his delay does not mean that he has
denied you. Actually, I've discovered
that
when we saw from delay, it has got a way
of activating our faith to trust more in
our God. It has a way of making us
remain awake and calling upon the name
of the Lord. Meaning that the delay
should not
MAKE YOU GO BACK TO THE WORLD OR STOP
TRUSTING the Lord. It should DRAW YOU
CLOSER AND nearer to the Lord. And so my
brethren, this evening God is here to
help us
and especially in that area of
discouragements and disappointments. As
we go through a few scriptures, you will
discover that you are not THE ONLY ONE.
MEN of old and men of the Bible went
through them, but they never put off
their eyes from THE LORD. THE MORE they
suffered from disappointments and
discouragements, the more they kept
trusting the Lord. And at the end, the
Lord came through for them. And if he
did for them, he can do it for us this
evening because he's the same God. The
Bible says, Jesus Christ the same
yesterday, let us go on.
And forevermore. So, he is there
yesterday, today, and forevermore. So,
as he was with them, so he is with us.
And so, tonight we want to trust the
Lord that he's going to speak to us. So,
I want to share
from a message entitled, "It Shall Be
Well."
It shall be well.
And uh
when I say it shall be well, you can put
whatever you want it to be well in your
life. It shall be well with me because
of the nature of my work, my family,
name it. You know, it shall be well.
Why? And so forth and so on. So, uh
let us read from the book of Isaiah.
Isaiah 3:10
only.
It is says
just I read this one verse for now. It
is says say to the righteous that shall
be well with them.
For they shall eat the fruit
of their doing.
Just pause there and leave it there.
Uh, this is a very defiant statement of
us that Isaiah spoke to the children of
Judah.
This time uh, Judah had gone through
hard moments. And because of that, they
had denied the Lord. If you read from
verse 1 to verse 9, you see them they
had gone astray and they had followed
their own things. They had decided to
worship idols. THEY HAD DECIDED TO REBEL
against God. They were NOT SERVING THE
GOD of Israel as it was. THEY HAD TURNED
AWAY from from him. AND ISAIAH CAME and
spoke this word. And this verse is
drawing a parallel
between the rebellious people and the
obedient people, between the unrighteous
and THE RIGHTEOUS. SO, HE HAS TALKED
SPECIFICALLY TO THE RIGHTEOUS. WHAT WHAT
he's saying is that though living in the
I MEAN, ALTHOUGH PEOPLE HAVE DENIED THE
LORD, THOUGH PEOPLE [screaming] HAVE
GONE ASTRAY, THOUGH PEOPLE HAVE DECIDED
TO WORSHIP IDOLS, THOUGH PEOPLE HAVE
REBELLED AGAINST THE TRUE GOD, THERE IS
A GENERATION THAT HAS SAID WE ARE NOT
GOING TO BOW TO IDOLS. WE ARE GOING TO
KEEP ON PUTTING OUR TRUST IN THE LORD.
AND HE SAYS, "SAY TO THE RIGHTEOUS, SO
AMONG THE WICKED, THEY WILL FOUND SOME
PEOPLE WHO HAD PUT THEIR TRUST IN THE
LORD. AND THEY ARE THE ONES WHO ARE
BEING REFERRED TO AS THE RIGHTEOUS. AND
THIS EVENING, I WANT TO TALK TO THE
PEOPLE WHO ARE LIVING IN A WICKED
GENERATION BUT DECLARING THE GOODNESS OF
THE LORD. THOSE WHO HAVE SAID, "NO TO
EVIL. THOSE WHO HAVE SAID, "I CAN'T BOW
[screaming] TO THIS WICKEDNESS. THOSE
WHO HAVE SAID, "I CAN'T DO THIS WICKED
THING." THOUGH EVERYBODY SEEMS TO BE IN
DOING WHAT IS EVIL, THERE IS A
GENERATION. IT IS CALLED THE GENERATION
OF THE RIGHTEOUS. IT SHALL BE WELL WITH
THEM. AND TONIGHT, AS YOU ARE SEATED
THERE, MAY IT BE WELL WITH YOU. AS YOU
SAY NO TO THE WORLD, AS YOU SAY NO TO
WORLDLINESS, AS YOU SAY NO TO EVIL, AS
YOU SAY NO TO THAT WHICH IS UNGODLY, MAY
IT BE WELL WITH YOU TO THE GLORY OF the
name of THE LORD JESUS CHRIST.
HALLELUJAH. SO, THE RECIPIENTS, WHEN
THEY heard about that, ASKED THE
FOLLOWING QUESTIONS. BUT WHEN THEY HEARD
THAT IT SHALL BE WELL WITH THEM, THE
RIGHTEOUS, WHEN THEY HEARD THAT, THEY
HAD question marks. The first one is,
"When shall it be well with us?"
THEY ALSO ASKED, "HOW SHALL IT BE WELL
WITH US?" THEY ALSO ASKED, "WHERE SHALL
IT BE WELL?"
AND THEN, "HOW SHALL IT BE WELL?" AND
THE FINAL QUESTION IS, "TO WHO SHALL IT
BE WELL?" I MEAN, THEY HAD THOSE
QUESTIONS. HOW WILL IT BE? WHEN WILL IT
BE? HOW WILL IT BE WELL WITH US? BUT LET
ME TELL YOU, WHAT WILL MAKE IT BE WELL
WITH THEM IS THIS ONE WORD. IT IS SAYS
IT IS TO THE RIGHTEOUS. THE RIGHTEOUS,
IT SHALL BE WELL WITH THEM. AND THEN
DOWN THERE, WHAT DOES IT SAY? THEY SHALL
EAT THE FRUIT OF THEIR DOINGS. AND THIS
EVENING, WHAT WE ARE SAYING IS IT
DOESN'T MATTER WHAT I HAVE LOST. DOESN'T
MATTER WHAT I'M GOING THROUGH. I HAVE TO
EAT THE GOOD OF THE I MEAN, I HAVE TO
EAT THE FRUIT OF MY DOINGS. ANOTHER
VERSION SAYS BY LABOR. WHAT YOU ARE
DOING, MY BROTHER, MY SISTER, YOU WILL
EAT THE GOOD OF THE WORK OF YOUR HANDS
TO THE GLORY OF GOD. SO, UH
I mean, this declaration
SHOWS
HOW THE RIGHTEOUS ARE PRESERVED by God.
IT IS SHOWS THE IMPORTANCE OF BEING a
righteous man.
IT IS SHOWS HOW GOD VALUES THE
RIGHTEOUS. IT IS SHOWS HOW THE RIGHTEOUS
IS
IS in good hands OF THE LORD AND HOW THE
EYES OF THE LORD ARE ON THE RIGHTEOUS.
AND HE ENCOURAGES THEM ALTHOUGH THE REST
OF THE PEOPLE ARE WICKED. I CAN SEE
THERE'S A GENERATION. AND HE SAYS THIS
GENERATION OF THE RIGHTEOUS IT SHALL EAT
THE good of of the land. And this
evening, brethren, LET US KNOW THAT
THERE IS GOOD OF THE LAND WHICH WE ARE
SUPPOSED TO EAT. WHY? BECAUSE WE ARE
RIGHTEOUS. IN THE BOOK OF ISAIAH, LET'S
SEE CHAPTER 1 verse 19.
Let's see what it says. ISAIAH 1:19.
IF YOU ARE WILLING
and obedient, you shall eat the good of
the land. Look at that.
Willingness and obedience
THEN IS EQUALS to eating the good OF THE
LAND.
WILLINGNESS AND OBEDIENCE TO GOD, IT HAS
GOT SOME FRUITS WHICH WE ARE SUPPOSED TO
EAT. LET ME TELL YOU, BRETHREN,
UH WHEN WE ARE TALKING OF WILLINGNESS
AND OBEDIENCE, WE ARE TALKING OF OBEYING
AND WALKING THE WAYS OF THE LORD. IT IS
KNOWING THAT YOU HAVE BEEN REDEEMED FROM
THE WORLD. IT IS MAKING SURE THAT THERE
IS NO WORLDLINESS IN YOUR LIFE. IT IS
MAKING SURE THAT YOUR WAYS UH UH IN
GOOD TITIUNO TOWN WITH GOD. YOU ARE
WALKING RIGHT. YOU HAVE THE UPRIGHTNESS
OF THE LORD WORKING IN YOUR LIFE. THEN
SUCH A PERSON, BECAUSE HE IS A WILLING
and obedient, HE SHALL EAT THE GOOD OF
THE LAND. THE LAND WE ARE LIVING IN, IT
HAS GOT SO MANY GOOD THINGS, BRETHREN.
THIS EVENING I'M SAYING, MAY YOU EAT THE
GOOD OF THE LAND.
MAY THAT UH THAT THAT POSITION AT YOUR
PLACE OF WORK BE GIVEN TO YOU SO THAT
YOU MAY EAT THE GOOD OF THE LAND. MAY
YOUR BUSINESS FLOURISH SO THAT YOU MAY
EAT THE GOOD OF THE LAND. MAY YOUR
PRAYERS BE ANSWERED THAT YOU MAY EAT THE
GOOD OF THE LAND. MAY YOUR [screaming]
YOUR MINISTRY FLOURISH THAT YOU MAY EAT
THE GOOD OF THE LAND. MAY YOUR
RELATIONSHIP BE SOLID THAT YOU MAY EAT
THE GOOD OF THE LAND IN THE NAME OF
JESUS. OBEDIENCE AND WILLINGNESS
>> [screaming]
>> ARE TWO KEY THINGS FOR GOD TO MAKE YOU
EAT THE GOOD OF THE LAND. IF YOU HAVE
BEEN LIVING IN REBELLION AND
DISOBEDIENCE, LET ME TELL YOU TONIGHT,
WE ARE GOING TO DROP THAT SO THAT WE MAY
PICK ON THE WILLINGNESS AND OBEDIENCE OF
GOD THAT WE MAY EAT THE GOOD OF THE LAND
[screaming] TO THE GLORY OF GOD THE
FATHER IN JESUS' NAME. HALLELUJAH.
SO NOW, WHEN WE ARE TALKING ABOUT THAT,
IT IS VERY NECESSARY TO KNOW
THAT
NOT EVEN AT THIS TIME
WHEN PEOPLE HAVE TURNED AWAY FROM GOD,
THEY TURNED AWAY FROM GOD DURING THE
TIME OF ISAIAH,
DURING THE TIME OF NOAH, THEY ALSO
TURNED AWAY FROM THE LORD. IN THE BOOK
OF GENESIS,
let's go there in Genesis 6
5 to 8.
GENESIS 6:5-8 SAYS, "THEN THE LORD SAW
THAT THE WICKEDNESS OF THE MAN WAS GREAT
in the earth.
And that every intent of the thoughts of
his heart was only EVIL CONTINUALLY."
LOOK AT THIS. NOAH IS LIVING IN THE
MIDDLE OF SUCH PEOPLE
WHOSE HEARTS ARE AWAY FROM THE LORD. AND
IT IS AS IF HE IS ALONE.
AND EVERYBODY IS, YOU KNOW, FOLLOWING
HIS OWN WAYS. THE WICKEDNESS IS GROWING
FROM BAD TO WORSE DAY AFTER DAY.
AND EVERY INTENT, THE THOUGHTS OF MEN,
UH AND THEIR HEARTS WAS ONLY EVIL
CONTINUALLY. THERE WAS EVIL EVERYWHERE.
VERSE 6 SAYS, "AND THE LORD WAS SORRY
THAT HE HAD MADE MAN ON THE EARTH. AND
HE WAS GRIEVED IN HIS HEART."
THEN 7, "SO THE LORD SAID, 'I WILL
DESTROY MAN WHOM I HAVE CREATED from the
face of the earth, BOTH MAN AND BEAST,
CREEPING THING AND BIRDS OF THE AIR, FOR
I AM SORRY that I made man. Verse 8 is
the one I wanted most. But Noah found
grace
in the eyes of the Lord. HALLELUJAH.
SO HE'S LIVING AMONG WICKED PEOPLE. AND
EVERYBODY FROM MORNING TO EVENING, HE'S
THINKING AND DOING THAT WHICH IS WICKED.
HE HAS NO TIME TO THINK FOR ANYTHING
RIGHTEOUS. AND NOAH IS LIVING AMONG
THEM. THIS NOAH, WHEN HE'S LIVING AMONG
THEM, HIS EYES WERE UPON THE LORD, LIKE
WE SAW IN ISAIAH 3:10.
AND THEN NOAH IN HIS, YOU KNOW,
OBEDIENCE TO THIS GOD, GOD CAME to him.
AND HE HE WAS MADE I MEAN TOLD TO MAKE
AN ARK. BUT BEFORE THAT, WHAT WAS THIS
THAT GOD SAVED NOAH FROM THE FLOOD? IT'S
BECAUSE HE FOUND GRACE IN THE EYES OF
THE LORD. HOW WOULD YOU SAY NOAH WAS
RIGHTEOUS? HOW WOULD YOU SAY NOAH WAS
AFTER GOD'S HEART? HOW WOULD YOU SAY
NOAH AND HIS FAMILY WERE SERVANTS OF
GOD? BUT THERE IS SOMETHING THAT MADE
HIM BE SAVED FROM THE THE FLOOD, THE
GRACE OF GOD. HE FOUND GRACE. IN OTHER
VERSIONS, IT SAYS HE FOUND FAVOR BEFORE
GOD. AND SO THIS EVENING, THIS IS THE
FAVOR WE NEED, BRETHREN, THAT WE MAY
WALK [screaming] RIGHTEOUSLY IN THE LAND
OF THE LIVING. WHEN WE ARE LIVING AMONG
WICKED PEOPLE, WHEN YOU WE ARE WORKING
WITH THE WICKED PEOPLE, WHEN EVERY OTHER
PERSON SEEMS TO BE FOLLOWING THE WAYS OF
THE DEVIL, TIME HAS COME THAT WE MAY
FIND FAVOR BEFORE THE LORD, AND THE LORD
WILL SAVE US. SO IT IT IS NOT YOU, NOT
[screaming] ONLY YOU AND ME. ALL ARE
LIVING AMONG WICKED PEOPLE. SIN IS
EVERYWHERE. BUT LET ME TELL YOU, EVEN
WHEN THINGS ARE ARE THAT WAY, IT SHALL
BE WELL WITH YOU.
WHY? BECAUSE OF THE FAVOR OF GOD. YEAH,
NEW KING AND NEW INTERNATIONAL VERSION
SAYS, "BUT NOAH FOUND FAVOR IN THE EYES
OF THE LORD." MAY YOU FIND FAVOR IN THE
HOUSE OF THE LORD. AND BECAUSE OF THAT
FAVOR, MAY YOUR BUSINESS FLOURISH.
BECAUSE OF THE FAVOR OF GOD, MAY YOU
FIND THAT YOU LOVED ONE YOU'VE BEEN
[screaming] PRAYING FOR. BECAUSE OF THE
FAVOR OF GOD, MAY YOU SECURE THAT JOB
YOU'VE BEEN BELIEVING THE LORD FOR.
BECAUSE OF THE FAVOR OF GOD, MAY YOUR
MARRIAGE REMAIN SOLID IN JESUS' NAME.
MAY [screaming] THE NAME OF THE LORD BE
PRAISED IN YOUR HOME. BECAUSE OF THE
FAVOR OF THE LORD, MAY YOUR CHILDREN BE
TURNED TO YOU IN THE NAME OF JESUS.
BECAUSE OF THE FAVOR OF GOD, MAY YOUR
MINISTRY FLOURISH IN JESUS' NAME.
BECAUSE OF THE FAVOR OF GOD, MAY YOU
PASS THAT EXAM IN JESUS' NAME. BECAUSE
[screaming] OF THE FAVOR OF GOD, MAY YOU
GET THAT JOB YOU'VE BEEN BELIEVING THE
LORD FOR. FAVOR IS WHAT YOU NEED. TO THE
GLORY OF GOD, WE CAN ARISE AND SAY, "IT
SHALL BE WELL WITH ME BECAUSE I WALK IN
THE FAVOR OF GOD. BECAUSE WHEN WE ARE
TALKING OF FAVOR,
GOD IS GREATER. GRACE, [screaming]
WE SAY GRACE IS UNMERITED FAVOR.
UNMERITED IS SOMETHING YOU ARE GIVEN,
NOT BECAUSE YOU MERITED FOR IT OR YOU'VE
DONE ANYTHING FOR IT. SOMEBODY COMES AND
GIVES YOU A THOUSAND, NOT THAT YOU
QUALIFY for it. YOU ARE JUST GIVEN. THIS
WHAT WE CALL FAVOR. AND THIS EVENING,
PEOPLE ARE GOING TO SECURE THINGS SOME
[screaming] THEY HAVE NEVER PRAYED FOR.
THOSE I'M GOING TO OPEN BEFORE YOU.
THOSE YOU HAVE NEVER KNOCKED AT. AND YOU
WILL WALK THROUGH THEM. WHY? BECAUSE OF
THE FAVOR OF GOD. SOME OF YOU WILL BE
BLESSED UNTIL YOU WONDER WHETHER THIS
BLESSING WAS MINE.
>> [screaming]
>> WHY? BECAUSE OF THE FAVOR OF GOD. SOME
OF YOU WILL SIT IN BIG BOATS. NOT
BECAUSE OF ANYTHING ELSE, BUT BECAUSE OF
THE FAVOR OF GOD. AND [screaming] THIS
EVENING WHAT WE ARE SAYING, THE LORD OF
FAVOR IS IN OUR MINISTER. AND HE'S GOING
TO LIFT YOU FROM YOUR SITUATION. HE'S
GOING TO LIFT YOU FROM YOUR STATE. HE'S
GOING TO LIFT YOU FROM WHERE YOU ARE
STUCK. GOD OF FAVOR IS [screaming]
COMING THROUGH FOR YOU. LET ME TELL YOU
TONIGHT, THE GOD OF FAVOR IS HERE.
>> [screaming]
>> AND HE'S GOING TO LIFT SOMEBODY. AS YOU
GO HOME, YOU WILL GO UNDER THE FAVOR OF
GOD. [screaming] AND I'M SAYING NEW
THINGS ARE GOING TO HAPPEN IN YOUR LIFE.
NOT BECAUSE OF POWER, NO MIGHT, BUT
BECAUSE OF THE SPIRIT OF THE LORD. THE
FAVOR OF GOD. MAY THIS FAVOR WORK IN
YOUR LIFE IN THE NAME OF JESUS. MAY THE
FAVOR OF GOD COME UPON YOU [screaming]
TONIGHT IN JESUS' NAME. MAY THE LORD
LIFT YOU FROM YOUR SITUATION BECAUSE OF
HIS FAVOR. MAY YOU GET [screaming]
THINGS YOU HAVE NEVER WORKED FOR BY THE
NAME OF THE LORD BECAUSE OF HIS FAVOR IN
JESUS' NAME. HALLELUJAH. [screaming]
GLORY TO GOD. THE FAVOR OF GOD IS WHAT
WE NEED. LET ME TELL YOU, EVEN IF IT
COMES AT A TIME WHEN YOU DISCOVER THAT
UH
THIS WORK OF FAITH IS BECOMING
CHALLENGING. DAY AFTER DAY, YOU ARE
GETTING CHALLENGED DAY AFTER DAY. LET ME
TELL YOU, WE DON'T CONTINUE DAY AFTER
DAY BECAUSE WE ARE GIANTS OF FAITH. IT
IS BY THE FAVOR OF GOD. IT IS BY THE
GRACE OF GOD THAT WE WAKE UP IN THE
MORNING AND DECLARE AND SAY TODAY, I'LL
WALK IN THE WAYS OF THE LORD. I'LL LIVE
A CHILD OF GOD. I'LL LIVE A VICTORIOUS
LIFE. TODAY,
>> [screaming]
>> I'M GOING TO BE A CONQUEROR AND NOT A
VIC- I MEAN A VICTIM. I'LL BE A VICTOR
NOT A VICTIM. I'LL BE [screaming] ABOVE
ONLY AND NOT BELOW. I'LL BE THE HEAD AND
NOT THE TAIL. THAT DECLARATION
[screaming] SHOWS THE KIND OF A PERSON
YOU ARE AND THAT IS OUR PORTION IN
JESUS' NAME. PRAISE THE LORD.
I WANT TO ASK YOU TO SEE ANOTHER PERSON
HERE BY THE NAME LOT.
LOT IN THE BOOK of Genesis
chapter 19
17 to 19 and then we will go to 24.
Genesis
verses 17 to 18 to to 18 and then we
shall I mean to 19. Then we shall go to
24. Look at this man
by the NAME LOT.
BIBLE SAYS
as soon as they had brought them out
they here are the angels.
Out from where?
FROM SODOM.
ONE of them said FLEE FOR YOUR LIVES.
DON'T LOOK BACK.
DON'T STOP ANYWHERE IN THE PLAIN. FLEE
THE MOUNTAINS.
I MEAN FLEE TO the mountains or you will
be swept away. 18.
But Lot SAID TO THEM, "NO, MY LORDS.
PLEASE
YOUR SERVANT HAS FOUND FAVOR." LOOK AT
THAT WORD AGAIN.
in your EYES AND YOU HAVE SHOWN GREAT
KINDNESS TO ME
IN SPARING MY LIFE. BUT I CAN'T FLEE TO
THE MOUNTAINS. THIS DISASTER WILL
OVERTAKE ME and I'll die."
24.
THEN THE LORD RAINED DOWN
BURNING SULFUR
ON SODOM AND GOMORRAH from the Lord
out of the heavens. Look at this man.
He's living in the middle of VERY WICKED
PEOPLE.
IMMORALITY IN SODOM AND GOMORRAH WAS THE
THING OF THE DAY.
AND NOW I'M GOD HIMSELF SAW THE
WICKEDNESS OF THOSE CITIES AND HE CAME
DOWN TO DESTROY THEM. HE SENT HIS ANGELS
TO GO AND DESTROY THEM. SO, WHEN THE
ANGELS ENTERED INTO THAT CITY
uh from Abraham who had INTERCEDED FOR
HIS NEPHEW LOT, THEY WENT AND entered in
his house.
When you read, YOU SEE HOW THE PEOPLE OF
THE CITY GATHERED AND THEY WERE ASKING
FOR THESE THREE MEN
WHO APPEARED TO BE MEN, BUT THEY WERE
ANGELS.
AND THEY WANTED TO THEM TO COME OUT SO
THAT THEY MAY UH
uh and that they may know them.
Know them. So,
LOT SAID, "NO, IT'S NOT POSSIBLE." SO,
HE STRUCK I MEAN, THE ANGEL STRUCK THEM
WITH BLINDNESS. And then when the
morning was about to come, no
uh Lot,
his wife and two daughters, they were
rescued.
And this is not the story. BUT, THE
QUESTION IS HOW WHAT MADE UH LOT and his
wife and children the two daughters TO
BE SPARED? IT IS BECAUSE OF THE FAVOR OF
GOD. NOT THAT LOT WAS RIGHTEOUS. NOT
THAT LOT FEARED THE LORD. ONE IS
>> [screaming]
>> UH UNCLE
UM Abraham had interceded for him.
YEAH?
SO, HE IS SPARED FROM THIS FIRE THAT
CAME DOWN FROM HEAVEN. THOUGH HE AMONG
US WE CAN BE PEOPLE AND THIS WHAT WE ARE
SAYING BRETHREN. AS A CHURCH, WE NEED
THE LORD TO SPARE US EVEN DURING
CALAMITIES, DURING INCURABLE DISEASES,
DURING THINGS THAT YOU KNOW MAY COME ON
OUR WAY.
THAT WE MAY FIND FAVOR BEFORE GOD. AND
THIS SAME GOD WHO SHOWS FAVOR TO PEOPLE
HE IS THE SAME GOD WE ARE WORSHIPPING
THIS EVENING. AND AS HE SHOWED FAVOR TO
THEM, AS HE SPARED LOT FROM THIS FIRE OF
SILVER, HE IS ABLE TO SPARE YOU FROM ANY
DISEASE, FROM ANY SICKNESS, FROM ANY
CALAMITY, FROM FAMINE, FROM ANY DANGER.
HE IS ABLE TO SPARE US. AND LET ME TELL
YOU, NOT BECAUSE YOU ARE THAT RIGHTEOUS,
BUT THE FAVOR OF GOD WILL LIFT YOU UP.
AND THE SAME GOD WHO SAVED THEM FROM
THOSE CALAMITIES, HE IS ABLE TO SAVE US
TONIGHT.
THE SAME GOD, HE IS ABLE TO SAVE US
TONIGHT. AND HE WILL SAVE YOU AND HE
WILL SAVE ME TO THE GLORY and honor of
his name. In Jesus' name. Praise the
living God.
AMEN. SO THE ENEMIES MAY BE THERE. HARD
MOMENTS MAY BE THERE. BUT LET ME TELL
YOU, WE ARE SUPPOSED TO REJOICE IN THE
LORD. LET'S SEE MICAH. MICAH 7:8.
BOOK of Micah
7 and 8.
HERE IS AN DEFIANT STATEMENT HERE.
Look at what Micah IS SAYING. DO NOT
GLOAT OVER ME.
Let's see.
New King James version.
SAYS, "DO NOT REJOICE OVER ME, MY ENEMY.
When I fall,
I will arise. When I sit in darkness,
the Lord will be light to me. Let me say
this.
THIS IS AN DEFIANT STATEMENT OF US. IT
SAYS, IT DOES NOT MATTER WHAT I AM GOING
THROUGH. IT DOES NOT MATTER, YOU KNOW,
WHAT I HAVE LOST. IT DOES NOT MATTER
WHAT HAS HAS HAPPENED TO ME. ONE THING I
KNOW, YOUR ENEMY REJOICE NOT OVER ME. IN
JESUS' NAME, BECAUSE WHEN I FALL, I WILL
RISE AGAIN. EVEN IF I'VE BEEN DARKNESS,
THE LORD WILL BE A LIGHT TO ME. MEANING,
IT DOES NOT MATTER THE SITUATION WE ARE
IN. WE HAVE OUR GOD WHO IS MIGHTY. SO,
MAY THE [screaming] DEVIL NOT BRAG
TONIGHT THAT HE HAS FIXED YOU. THE DEVIL
SHOULD NOT BRAG TONIGHT THAT HE HAS PUT
YOU AT A CORNER. UH OH,
>> [screaming]
>> YOU HAVE LOST THIS AND THE OTHER. OH,
YOU HAVE FOUND YOURSELF ENDED INTO MESS
SPIRITUALLY. YOU MIGHT HAVE DENIED THE
LORD BECAUSE OF ABCD. WHAT THE BIBLE IS
SAYING IS THAT THE DEVIL SHOULD NOT
REJOICE OVER US BECAUSE OF OUR
SITUATION. LET NOT THE DEVIL REJOICE
OVER WHAT YOU HAVE YOU WHAT HAS HAPPENED
TO YOU. BECAUSE OUR GOD WILL MAKE US
RISE AGAIN. AND EVEN IF IT IS WE ARE
LIVING HARD MOMENTS, UNLESS I SEE WE ARE
IN DARKNESS, THE LORD WILL BE LIGHT TO
US. AND TONIGHT, I'M SAYING, MAY YOUR
DARKNESS BE TURNED TO LIGHT IN JESUS'
NAME. MAY THAT THING THAT SEEMS TO BE SO
DIFFICULT IN YOUR LIFE, MAY THEY BE
TURNED AROUND BY THE LORD AND BECOME
VERY EASY. MAY THE LORD TURN OUR
SITUATIONS, YES, UH TO US. [screaming]
AND MAY HE GIVE US VICTORY. AND MAY HE
GIVE US POWER TO OVERCOME SO THAT THE
ENEMY WILL NOT REJOICE OVER US. LET THE
DEVIL KNOW THAT THE GOD WE SERVE IS A
GOD OF A SECOND CHANCE. IT DOES NOT
MATTER WHAT YOU HAVE LOST. IT DOES NOT
MATTER WHAT YOU HAVE GONE THROUGH. WE
SERVE A GOD OF A SECOND CHANCE. WHEN WE
SEEM TO HAVE FALLEN, WE SHALL ARISE
AGAIN. SO, WE SHAKE OFF THE DUST AND WE
SAY, "HERE I AM." YES, AS THOUGH NOTHING
HAPPENED TO YOU. YOU SHAKE OFF THE DUST.
YOU ARISE AND SAY, "I AM GOING TO MOVE
ON." LET ME TELL YOU, BROTHER, TONIGHT.
THE TIME HAS COME THAT WE MAY TELL THE
DEVIL THAT HE SHOULD NOT REJOICE OVER US
WHEN WE HAVE FALLEN, WHEN WE HAVE LOST
IT, THAT WHEN THAT HAS HAPPENED TO YOU.
WE HAVE A GOD WHO IS ABLE TO RISE US UP
OR TO LIFT US UP. AND IN HIS NAME, WE
ARISE. [screaming]
AND EVEN IF WE ARE IN DARKNESS, HE WILL
COME AND SHINE HIS LIGHT TO US IN JESUS'
NAME. AND SO, THIS EVENING, LET US GET
ENCOURAGED AND KNOW THAT WE HAVE A GOD
IN HEAVEN WHO IS ABLE TO COME THROUGH
FOR US. THE DARKNESS IS ABLE TO BE
TURNED INTO LIGHT IN JESUS' NAME. SO,
THE DEVIL SHOULD NOT
REJOICE OVER US. WHY? BECAUSE WE HAVE
SOME ELASTICITY IN US.
THAT RESILIENCE THAT WORKS IN US.
THAT KIND OF POWER
THAT LIVES US. IT INDWELLS US. AND SO,
EVEN WHEN WE, YOU KNOW, WE SEEM TO HAVE
TO BE LOSING IT, WE BOUNCE BACK AND MOVE
AS THOUGH NOTHING HAPPENED TO US. AND
TONIGHT, I WANT TO TELL YOU THERE IS
POWER [screaming] IN RESILIENCE. THERE'S
POWER IN ELASTICITY. STRETCH YOUR FIBER.
[screaming] YOU ARE ELASTICITY. AND
ARISE AND SAY, "I AM GOING TO CONQUER. I
WILL NOT BE DOWN FOREVER. [screaming]
THIS IS MY EVENING TO RISE UP AGAIN.
THIS IS MY DAY TO RISE UP AGAIN. THIS IS
MY HOUR [screaming] TO RISE UP AGAIN.
WHY? BECAUSE THE LORD IS MY VICTORY. AND
IN HIS NAME [screaming] I'M GOING TO
TAKE A NEW STEP AND BECOME AS THOUGH I
HAD NOT LOST. BRETHREN, LET US SHAKE OFF
THAT DUST. LET US LET GO [screaming]
THAT THING THAT YOU HAVE BEEN HOLDING
ON. LET US ACCEPT WHAT HAS PASSED AS
PAST. LET US ARISE [screaming]
AND SAY I AM GOING TO DO IT AGAIN IN THE
NAME OF JESUS. LET ME TELL YOU, YOUR
YESTERDAY MAY BE YOUR GREATEST ENEMY FOR
YOUR TOMORROW BECAUSE YOU ARE HOLDING
THINGS THAT YOU CANNOT REVERSE BECAUSE
ONE THING YOU CAN'T CHANGE YOUR
YESTERDAY. YOU CAN'T CHANGE WHAT
HAPPENED YESTERDAY. WHAT YOU CAN CHANGE
IS WHAT IS HAPPENING TOMORROW.
[screaming] YOU CAN MAKE A DECISION THAT
TOMORROW WILL NOT BE LIKE YESTERDAY. I
MISSED IT YESTERDAY, BUT TOMORROW I'M
GOING TO GAIN IT. I LOST IT YESTERDAY,
TOMORROW I'LL BE A VICTOR. I AM GOING TO
OVERCOME IN JESUS NAME. SO, LET
[screaming] GO.
YOUR YESTERDAY'S DEFEATS.
ANY KIND OF A MENTAL PICTURE OF YOUR
YESTERDAY, PLEASE, IT CANNOT HELP YOU.
IT MAY BE SO GOOD. YOU MAY CRY OVER IT,
BUT YOU CAN'T CHANGE IT. WHEN IT IS
GONE, IT IS GONE, BUT YOU CAN CHANGE
YOUR TOMORROW. CAN WE FOCUS ON OUR
FUTURE BECAUSE WE CAN CHANGE IT. CAN WE
FOCUS ON OUR TOMORROW BECAUSE WE CAN
CHANGE IT. CAN WE FOCUS ON OUR FUTURE
BECAUSE WE HAVE THE ABILITY TO CHANGE
IT. WE CAN PRAY [screaming] OVER IT AND
THINGS CAN TAKE A NEW TWIST. BUT
YESTERDAY'S THINGS YOU CAN'T CHANGE IT.
SO, WHY SHOULD WE BE CRYING [screaming]
FOR THINGS THAT HAPPENED YESTERDAY? THAT
FRIEND OF YOURS WHO DROPPED YOU
YESTERDAY, YOU'VE BEEN HOLDING ON HIM.
YOU'VE [screaming] BEEN HOLDING ON HER.
BUT THE TRUTH OF THE MATTER IS, MY
FRIEND, YOU WERE DROPPED.
ACCEPT IT.
IT IS GONE.
AND THEN TRUST IN THE LORD. AND TELL THE
LORD, I'M BOUNCING BACK AGAIN. AND I AM
GOING TO TRUST IN YOUR NAME THAT YOU ARE
GOING TO BRING THE RIGHT ONE. SO,
ANYTHING IN THE PAST, LET IT GO AND LET
US FOCUS IN THE FUTURE. AND THE LORD
WILL BLESS US. THE FAVOR OF GOD WILL
WORK IN OUR LIVES. IT SHALL BE WELL WITH
US. SURELY, IT IS IN THE FUTURE. SO,
TOMORROW, IT SHALL BE WELL. TOMORROW,
[screaming]
THERE IS AN OPPORTUNITY FOR YOUR
EMPLOYMENT. TOMORROW, THERE IS AN
OPPORTUNITY FOR YOUR ENGAGEMENT.
TOMORROW, THERE'S AN OPPORTUNITY FOR
YOUR MARRIAGE. [screaming] YOU YOU YOU
WHAT? YOUR WEDDING IS THERE TOMORROW.
TOMORROW, THERE IS A NEW OFFICE FOR YOU.
>> [screaming]
>> TOMORROW, THERE IS AN UPLIFTING OF YOUR
MINISTRY. TOMORROW, [screaming]
THINGS WILL BE EVEN BETTER THAN
YESTERDAY. WHY? OUR GOD IS ABLE TO GIVE
US A BETTER TOMORROW.
SO, LET US DROP THESE THINGS THAT HAVE
BEEN THERE. AS I CONCLUDE,
here is a verse I want us to read.
This is a good one.
In the book of Job,
Job 14,
7, 42 to 10 and 16 to 17.
Let us first start with 14 to 7. Job Job
Job.
Job
14:7 says, "FOR THERE IS HOPE FOR A
TREE,
if it is cut down, that it will sprout
again,
AND THAT ITS TENDER ROOTS will not
cease. Now, this man who is speaking
these things,
he has gone through hell.
One day losing everything.
AND HIS BODY IS IN SORES.
Boils all over.
HE IS STINKING
TO AN EXTENT THAT HIS WIFE
HAS ALSO DENIED HIM.
AND HE IS THERE ALONE. THREE FRIENDS WHO
HAVE COME TO DISCOURAGE HIM EVEN THE
MORE. AND HE IS THERE. AND HIS EYES ARE
FIXED ON GOD. THEN HE ONE DAY HE GOT A
REVELATION. AND HE SAYS, "FOR THERE IS
HOPE IN A TREE." IN OTHER WORDS, THIS
TREE IS FIGURATIVE. IT IS HIM. HE IS
REFERRING TO HIMSELF. THAT HE IS THE
TREE. IF IT IS CUT DOWN, THAT IT WILL
SPROUT AGAIN, AND THAT ITS TENDER SHOOTS
WILL NOT CEASE. HE'S SAYING, "I, JOB,
HAVE GONE THROUGH HARD MOMENTS. ALL MY
WEALTH IS GONE. MY CHILDREN GONE ONE
DAY. NOW MY WIFE HAS DENIED ME, AND IS
TELLING ME TO CURSE MY GOD. MY FRIENDS
HAVE COME AND THEY ARE DISCOURAGING ME
THE MORE. I AM DOWN." AND THERE HE WAS
SCRATCHING HIMSELF EVERY DAY. IT IS THE
THE TIME THE TREE HAS BEEN CUT. AND
REMEMBER, THIS GUY WAS LIVING A VERY,
YOU KNOW,
I mean, he was A VERY RICH MAN.
HAD ALL SORTS OF ANIMALS. GOOD CHILDREN.
EVERYTHING TO HIM
WAS GOOD. AND HE WAS VERY RIGHTEOUS,
WALKING IN THE PRESENCE OF THE LORD.
THEN THE DEVIL CAME AND WANTED TO TEMPT
HIM THAT HE MAY DENY GOD. HE MAY REJECT
GOD. SO HE WENT THROUGH HELL. LET ME
TELL YOU, BRETHREN, YOU MIGHT HAVE LOST
A B C D, AND THAT IS NOT THE END. JOB IS
SAYING, "GIVE ME [screaming] TIME. I
WILL BOUNCE BACK TO MYSELF. I'M COMING
BACK AGAIN. DEVIL, [screaming] YOU HAVE
TOUCHED MY FAMILY, YOU'VE TOUCHED MY
WEATHER, YOU'VE TOUCHED MY BODY, BUT I'M
BOUNCING [screaming] BACK TO THE GLORY
OF GOD. AND YOU WILL SEE ME AND YOU WILL
BE SHOCKED." AND LET ME TELL YOU,
BRETHREN, THERE IS TIME TO BOUNCE BACK.
[screaming] AND I'M CALLING UPON
BRETHREN, BOUNCE BACK FROM THAT THING.
NO, IT IS NOT [screaming] THE END. GOD
IS NOT YET THROUGH WITH YOU. HE HAS A
LOT TO DO WITH YOU. HE'S ABOUT TO SHOW
UP [screaming] IN YOUR SITUATION. ARISE
AND THEN BOUNCE BACK AND SAY, "I AM NOT
GOING TO LIVE IN THIS SITUATION FOREVER.
[screaming] IT IS MY TIME TO ARISE."
THEN YOU ARISE AND TAKE YOUR POSITION IN
THE LORD AND SAY, "I AM [screaming]
GOING TO COME BACK." AND BECAUSE WHAT?
THAT IT WILL SPROUT AGAIN. AND THAT IS
TENDER SHOOT WILL NOT
>> [screaming]
>> SEIZE. HE WILL FLOURISH. AND THIS
EVENING, MAY YOU FLOURISH IN JESUS NAME.
IN WHATEVER YOU ARE DOING, WHEREVER YOU
ARE STUCK, MAY THE POWER OF GOD
[screaming] TAKE YOU OUT IN JESUS NAME.
MAY THE HAND OF THE LORD REACH OUT TO
YOU AND LIFT YOU IN JESUS NAME. LET'S
SAY 42 TO YEAH, 42.
That is chapter, sorry, chapter 42.
Verse 10.
Chapter 42:10 says, "AND THE LORD
RESTORED" THE BOUNCING BACK IS HERE.
"RESTORED [screaming]
JOB'S LOSSES WHEN HE PRAYED FOR his
friends. INDEED, THE LORD GAVE JOB TWICE
AS MUCH AS HE HAD BEFORE." THAT IS WHAT
I'M CALLING RESILIENCE, BOUNCING BACK.
HE HAS COME BACK.
>> [screaming]
>> THE LORD HAS HAD HIM. HE HAS SEEN HIS
PATIENCE. HE HAS SEEN HIS TRUST IN HIM.
THE LORD HAS COME THROUGH FOR JOB AND HE
HAS RESTORED JOB WHEN HE PRAYED FOR HIS
FRIENDS. IMMEDIATELY THE LORD GAVE JOB
TWICE AS MUCH, DOUBLE PORTION. MAY YOU
RECEIVE DOUBLE OF WHAT YOU HAVE LOST IN
THE NAME OF JESUS. MAY YOU WHAT YOU HAVE
LOST BE RESTORED DOUBLE IN THE NAME OF
JESUS. MAY YOU GET INTO ANOTHER LEVEL OF
LIFE THAT YOU HAVE NEVER EXPERIENCED
BEFORE IN JESUS' NAME. BOUNCE BACK
[screaming] AND THE SAME GOD OF OUR OF
JOB, HE IS OUR GOD. SO, HE HAS BOUNCED
[screaming] BACK AND HE'S COMING. AND
LET ME TELL YOU IN VERSE
THAT IS 42:10. YEAH.
UH VERSE 16 of the same, 16 and 17 of
verse two.
16. AFTER THIS, JOB LIVED 140
years and saw his children AND HIS
GRANDCHILDREN, FOUR GENERATIONS. 17.
SO, JOB DIED OLD AND FULL of days.
Who can deny that fact? Surely.
Where is this scientist who can deny
that?
Double.
You read up there, you see the kind of
daughters he got.
The most beautiful.
TELLING YOU.
WHY? HE
PUT HIS FAITH IN GOD.
>> In Jesus name, give me to bounce back.
Job did it and he sprang, you know,
to a level whereby friends came to see
this man who whom God has reached out to
him and transformed his life. May people
come to celebrate your successes.
Yes, may if they come and see you
graduating.
May they come and eat your cake on that
wedding day.
May they come and celebrate your
promotion at your place of work. May
they come AND SEE THE WONDERS IN YOUR
family in the NAME OF JESUS. WHY?
BECAUSE TONIGHT WE ARE BOUNCING BACK.
TONIGHT WE ARE ENTERING INTO A REALM OF
GOD'S FAVOR. TONIGHT WE ARE GOING TO SAY
OUR GOD IS FAITHFUL AND HE'S GOING to do
it for me and he will do it for you.
Shall we rise up?
As we get to a place of prayer,
let us
pray honest prayers. Tell the Lord where
it is aching most. Tell the Lord the
truth. Don't hide anything. Yeah, I know
what you have gone through, you can go
through. The The time God will conquer
for these people, he will conquer for
you. Hallelujah.
Brother Enoch,
get a place of prayer. Let us trust the
Lord. Let us pray than never before.